After I'd read over the amstrad technical documentationb, I started writing sprite routines, as I had a basic understanding of CPC screen memory from my youth, and something you could visually see when it was wrong seemed a good place to start, while I was working on the sprite routine, I started working out what I needed on paper, estimating how much memory I'd need for sprite data, and how the screen should be structured, I'd also come up with some ideas for the datastructures of the laevel layout and the like.

I knew CPU power would be very limited, so I needed to keep the backgrounds as simple as possible, I started writing a gradient background routine, and to my amazement it was faster than the firmware clear screen... but that was just the beginning, repeated rewrites later, and it had paralax scrolling, and I figured out how to use the stack pointer as a 'quick fill' and self modyfying code to really squeeze all the spare power out!


Memory was a real challence, because I owned a 464 with disk system as a child, so I could say I'd written a game like the ones I used to play– but this meant more challenges – the games screen-buffer was 32k, so half the ram was gone – and a further 8k was being used by the firmware – It was going to be a real struggle getting my game working on a 464 - and it seemed doubtful I would have enough memory for music, unless I could get that 8k from the firmware.

I wanted to program everything myself, but while I understand graphics modes and pixels, I am not well informed about sound or music, I decided that it was best to use the free Arkos player to give the game sound - without it I would have probably ended up with just bleeps and peeps and no music.

I wanted the game to play the same on 64k 464 and 128k 6128, but I didn't want to do anything like remove backgrounds on the 464 - as this would have meant the 6128 version was slower... instead I decided to split sprites into 2 banks for 2 frames of animation, the 6128 would use both, the 464 would use only 1

The original game had fast routines for 24x24 pixel sprites, and 'clipping' of sprites when the came onscreen only worked properly at this size - these  limitations no longer exist in the current game, but it meant splitting boss enemies into 24px strips to make them work without problems.

Each level added new tricks and effects.. custom enemy movements in level 2, 'submersion' effect in level 3 and supersized boss... illumination effects in 4.1 and vertical scroll in 4.2

By the last level I was getting pretty confident, and decided to have a huge bullet array of over 1000 bullets on the last boss battle, I had no idea how I could make it fast enough, but I had a feeling I'd pull it off!... it took 4 days to get it working, but I managed it!

Towards the end of the game I finally figured out how I could grab that 8k off the firmware... there was a trick to get the firmware to reinitialise itself... this allowed me to take all the memory for myself! this allowed me to use music on 464, and use a lookup table for screen locations - which was faster than calculating them!

I announced the game online, and started polishing the game off... but there was a big problem waiting for me!

Continued next week!