How did Chibi Akumas come about?

I'm going to start posting weekly chapters on the making of the original game, from the point of what it was like, and where the design ideas came from - I'm going move the 'technical' update to thursday to split the updates evenly

-----------------------

How did Chibi Akumas come about?

Well, I had been looking for a new programming project for a while, and I didn’t really feel satisfied by my recent windows or linux developments. While I had made some interesting projects I always seemed to forget everything I’d learned as soon as I had finished... and I was very frustrated with the Iphone game I wrote a few years ago, as due to OS upgrades and DRM I could not even use it on a modern Iphone or the development environment!


While reading the old Amstrad Action issues on the Archive.org website, I started thinking it might be fun to make my own new CPC game. When I was young I had frequently created little games and programs in Basic, but I had never tried assembly language and it would certainly make a change from the C++ and Visual basic development I’d done recently! Having decided I wanted to make a game, I now had to work out what!

After some thought and may dismissed poor ideas I gave up thinking of a game and started to think of what features I wanted the game to have. I decided I wanted to play with raster color switching – as the effect had always fascinated me and always seemed underused in games of the time.. .Because effect allows morecolors onscreen it seemed better to use Mode 1 – which gives 4 colors but good resolution and square pixels – this meant if I did the raster colors right, I could triple or quadruple the onscreen colors – which should certainly make the game look impressive!

As raster colors are constant across the screen, I decided the game should be a horizontally scrolling shooter, and as my favorite 2 such games were Death Smiles and Cotton – I liked the more gothic imagery of DeathSmiles, but wanted the humor of Cotton! I thought a dark and twisted game with a comedy styling would be really unique, also I was aware “Bullet hell” shooters were a relatively new concept which had only come to my attention in the last decade or so, I thought bringing one to the 80s cpc would bring something new to the platform, and would shift the focus to lots of small dots, rather than sprites which would avoid the CPC's weakness of not having hardware sprites!

There were two obvious problems to my plan – I had never programmed a game in assembly and had no idea if the CPC even had sufficient CPU power to do such a game – let alone if it was within my ability!

Tune in next week for the next part!