Chibiko Rising

Having decided on a bullet hell game, and wanting to make something with a 'Gothic Comedy style' I had to start thinking what the game would contain.

I didn't really want to just copy the Witch or Magical girl characters from other similar games, so I started trying to think of something of my own. Once again, I decided to let the CPC limitations make some choices for me, so I started looking at what my color limitations would be. As the 'raster palette switching' would make the colors of the player sprite change color I decided to just ignore that for the player character and 'pretend' the sprite was 4 shades of grey... however the CPC only has 3 shades (Black, Grey and White) so something 'equivalent' would be needed... the most plesent 4 colors were I decided on a 4 color gradient of Black,Purple,Cyan and White.

This meant no pink! so my character would have to have white skin - and purple hair! as I needed a flying character, I thought a Vampre would be perfect, and making the main character an antihero would make the game rather unusual! which was exactly I wanted.

I had decided to use plus sprites to avoid the raster colors making the player change color as much as possible – each plus sprite is 16x16 - and there's a limit of 16 onscreen, so making the main character 32x32 seemed a good choice as I had already decided wanted the game to be 2 player

Giving the character a big head made drawing the face and eyes a lot easier, the black ‘whites’ of the eyes were needed because her face was white - (I later used this to identify the 'Undead' from the 'Living' characters) – the bracelets were there to define her hands, and the simple dress and basic shoes were again what were visible to draw at low resolution with only 4 colors.
The big ‘ahoge’ giant strand of hair was a bit of a comic addition to the character – I was trying to put as much simple detail into the character as possible... I had read Mario's mustache and dungarees were to make the character clear at low resolution - and if Nintendo can make a company off their character - it would be a good enough design strategy.

The design of the levels of the first game were just a 'generic spooky journey' so went Mountain-Forest-River-Cave, and the source of the enemies were all over the place! usually I just tried to think of strange creepy things, like spliced faces, and skull monsters... but a few were more significant the bug with the mushroom in its back was something I'd seen in a nature magazine as a kid, and the 'Salary man zombie' was based on a dream i had where the office's 'Despatch department' had been turned into 'Despatch Zombies'... oh and the mukadebatci was a cross between the mukade and the suzumebachi - two highly poisonous bugs that everyone who lives in japan hates!

More to come next week!