Press Fire to Continue

Press Key For:

-----------------------



3d boss:

W A R N I N G ! ! !
A Unnessasarily Large Enemy
is approaching: Angler Grinder!


Hang on? Was there something
like this in mega man?!?


Er.. I kind of think there WAS!
Oh well, who gives a shit!




4th boss: 
W A R N I N G ! ! !

A Tiny Enemy is approaching
Necromancer: Vengeance!


W A R N I N G ! ! !"+&80
A shit load of enemy fire is"+&80
approaching:


THE OMEGA ARRAY!

Lets see what the Z80 can REALLY do!


-------------------------------








Your 'Chibiko Scoring System (TM)'
Rank was




Chibiko says


------


Subtitles1: 

Once Upon a time..
In a land far far away..
There was a girl who was kind
to everyone and brought happiness
everywhere She went !


Subtitles2: 
She isn't in this game!!



Subtitles3: 
Do you know what happens
when you die?



Subtitles4: 
They say 'if you're good
You go to a place of wonder where
all your dreams will come true



Subtitles5: 
But 'If you're bad, you'll go to
the OTHER PLACE Where you'll be
punished for the bad things you did!!


Subtitles6: 

Subtitles7: 
Chibiko was a typical cheerful girl.


She loved animals!

Subtitles9: 
And enjoyed spending time outdoors!


Subtitles10: 
Sometimes she was 'a bit' naughty

Subtitles11: 
And she didn't really like to study


Subtitles12: 
But one time she was very, very bad


Subtitles13: 
And took a 'prank' too far


Subtitles14: 
When someone does the unforgivable..


Subtitles15: 

Judgement comes from above!


Subtitles16: 
and strikes them once and for all!

Subtitles17: 
Really bad people don't go to heaven



Subtitles18: 
and even hell has its limit to
who they'll take!!

Subtitles19: 
You see, when people die,if they've
been 'Really Bad', they dont go
'up' or 'down'


Subtitles20: 
They stay where they were as undead
monsters, hated by God, and
feared by all mankind!
with an endless thirst for human blood!



Subtitles21: 
Subtitles22:
They live out eternity as Nosferatu
Vampires, cursed to live by feeding on
their former friends and companions!


-------------------------------------------------
Chibiko:You're the one sending all this
Shit?   Who the hell even are you?
You weren't in the intro, on the
web site or the title screen!!

LastBoss:So you've come for me at last?
Be Gone Foul Monster! 
I shall banish you from
this land once and for all


Chibiko:Yeah, yeah! whatever you say...
You better pray they have
haemorrhoid cream in the
afterlife...


Chibiko:Cos' I'm gonna kick your ass so hard
It'll hurt for a millennium!!


-------------------------------------------------


Chibiko:Yeah! Not so mouthy now are you!!
Now, Who the fuck are you?
Why are you creating these
monsters and invading my land??



LastBoss:I USED to be the Village elder
but since you raised the village
and killed all the villagers
I fled and hid in this cave!



Chibiko:	er..
well..
Yes, I did SORT-OF do THAT
But what about these monsters?




LastBoss:Huh, Monsters? These are the
animals that lived in the forest
The river got polluted, and they
got ill and mutated




Chibiko:um..
that was supposed to be a joke
hmm... But,
But why are you sending them to me?


LastBoss:I'm not doing that! Fire destroyed
their habitat,so now they
are migrating to better land
like the mountains.

Chibiko:ah...  Er... Um.. ahem!
Well... ah, this is akward  


Chibiko:I suppose I COULD cut down and
ONLY commit massacres every
other tuesday!!




Game Over!!
I hope you enjoyed playing this
game as much as I did making it!

See you again next time in
CHIBI AKUMA
Episode 2: Confrontation!

Thanks For Playing!!
Don't forget to turn off your set!

